José Romero

Relocating to CA | 443-848-0869 | jdromerov88@gmail.com | Website | Linkedin | Github

Full-Stack Web Developer

Full-Stack Web Developer with a passion for creating apps that solve problems and make people's lives easier. Experienced in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux with a background in Computer Engineering. Previous work experience as a Manager in the food service industry and as Computer Technician. I will also bring strong skills in team-building, employee training, customer service, team management, and creating working environments that encourage extraordinary results. Dependable, detail oriented, proficient multitasker and always willing to take on any task and learn something new. Conversational fluency in Spanish and Guarani.

Skills Languages

JavaScript, React, Redux, NodeJS, Ruby, Rails, SQL, HTML, CSS, Git, API, PostgreSQL, Linux, Wordpress.

English, Spanish, Guarani, Portuguese (basic).

Technical Projects

Flati//Life - GitHub Backend | GitHub Frontend | Live Demo

Social Network for Flatiron Students that aims to help new students survive bootcamp by curating a collection of fellow students projects and experiences. (SPA)

- + Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, projects, cohorts, technologies.
- Utilized BCrypt gem to stored encrypted user information.(server-side)
- + Built User Interface with React JS and managed states with Redux.
- + Utilized Semantic UI React framework with custom CSS.

Sports Buddy - GitHub

Single Page Application that helps users connect with people in their area to play sports.

- + Developed a Rails API backend using strong params, validations and endpoints for games, users, users_games.
- + Utilized postgresql for the database and gem BCrypt to encrypt the user information.
- + Utilized vanilla javascript with Semantic UI framework with custom CSS to build the User interface.

Vapor - GitHub Backend | Github Frontend

App that allows users to create a collection of games that they want to buy or already own. (SPA)

- + Constructed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, games, owned_games.
- + Utilized postgresql for the database and gem BCrypt to encrypt the user information.
- + Utilized RAWG Video Games Database API to pull and parse data of the games.
- + Built User Interface with React JS with Semantic UI React.

Experience

Web Developer, United Nations Volunteers (UNV) programme.

06/2020 - 08/2020

+ Developed Mercury Products website. Javascript, HTML, Bulma & Sass.

Apprentice General Manager, Chipotle, Washington DC, DC

05/2016 - 05/2019

- + Hired, trained, coached, and developed a 20+ member staff, with the express purpose of integrating talented individuals into a team capable of exceeding all customer and Chipotle corporate expectations with regard to service, food safety, and restaurant cleanliness.
- + Coordinated weekly scheduling for employees in order to effectively provide everyday services.
- + Played a key role in ensuring our location achieved it's annual sales and cash flow plan.

Computer Technician, Ministry of Agriculture and Livestock, San Ignacio, Paraguay

11/2009 - 06/2015

- + Provided IT support for the Department of Agriculture in the San Ignacio office: which involved installing PC software, problem solving hardware and internet connectivity issues, and acting as helpdesk support.
- + Increased inter-office understanding of Microsoft Office Suite capabilities through staff training seminars.
- + Ensured technology inventory control needs were consistently met by improving and developing inventory management processes and procedures.

Education

Flatiron School 10/2019 - 02/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Universidad Católica, San Ignacio Paraguay

2007 - 2012

Completed coursework in Computer Engineering; graduation pending thesis.